Harshitha Pulichintha

Hartford, CT 06106

harshithapulichinthav7fnd_6ru@indeedemail.com

+1 667 345 3565

Professional with 4 years of hands-on experience in the industry and academia equipped with strong knowledge in Data and

Business Analytics. Seeking a curated internship utilizing technical, analytical, and strategic skills. Available for internship from May to August and also open to full-time opportunities.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Student Administrative Assistant

Connecticut Education Network - Hartford, CT January 2022 to Present

- Managing workflows and supporting data migration from GRNOC to Salesforce.
- Working on creating a more personalized salesforce platform and generating sales and E-bid reports.
- Designed custom objects, fields, layouts, and custom reports for using report types.

Student Administrative Assistant

Connecticut Transportation Institute - Hartford, CT September 2021 to January 2022

- Inspected mapping, GPS data collection and developed GIS mapping of Connecticut using GIS software, Google, and Bing map to provide meaningful insights and ensure better road safety.
- Performed QA/QC after data entry by developing regression, normal probability, and scatter plots to maintain and monitor the quality of the data throughout the project using SQL.

Senior Business Analyst

Flutch - India

January 2020 to July 2021

- Developed unique user stories using JIRA and FeautureMap for a new launch product and categorized marketing strategies which resulted in an 18% ROI increase.
- Managed all analytical and business reporting for influencer markets including pricing and portfolio components and met

90% of roadblocks by investigating and correcting the roadblocks.

• Configured workflows in CRM & Salesforce and developed operational and marketing strategies helping stakeholders create more streamlined operations.

Product Analyst

HighRadius - India

June 2019 to December 2019

• Performed Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) on cash management services such as Order-to-Cash, Treasury and Risk

Management helping the sales and marketing teams to resolve existing issues and study various campaign performances.

- Developed a real-time content performance and engagement metrics dashboard using Google Analytics and Salesforce data to decrease time spent on data collection and analysis by 80%.
- Created a training, execution and best practices playbook and built a reporting and analytics dashboard to track the team's performance and growth.
- Developed and ran data audits and collaborated with IT teams to create visual and content modules in Salesforce to integrate them with leads, campaigns and opportunities enhancing the sales performance by 40%.

Business Analyst

Agrometrics - India January 2019 to May 2019

- Maintained and developed an association with clients across the US and Canada regarding the progress of agricultural markets.
- Prepared sales reports and performance reviews for leadership, defining clear objectives and opportunities necessary for the team to increase monthly sales by 10%.
- Analyzed functional and non-functional client requirements to design visually impactful dashboards and visualizations using Tableau and Excel. Reported key performance metrics of the potato markets resulting in an increase of process efficiency by 25%.

Data Analyst

FundsIndia - India May 2017 to December 2018

- Identified and monitored any discrepancies in the finance database and reduced the expenses by a significant 30% over 2 years. Standardized the operational metrics for reporting purposes.
- Created visual dashboards by scripting in R, Shiny and Markdown to illustrate Key Performance Indicators that drive customer investment patterns in mutual funds and stocks for the financial advisory team assisting them in prioritizing tasks.
- Identified customer drop-off patterns by performing analysis across the marketing funnel using Google Analytics and proposed corrective measures.
- Studied past revenue, customer trends & purchase patterns to draw inferences for strategic and managerial improvements and implemented trigger-based data capture and developed various stored procedures in SQL to generate various monthly and daily reports for strategic decisions.
- Compiled, evaluated, and maintained quantitative customer data for customer segmentation and reduced the annual churn from 13% to 10% with the development of customer churn model.

Education

Master of Science in MSBAPM

School of Business at University of Connecticut - Hartford, CT August 2021 to Present

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering

Vellore Institute of Technology - Vellore, Tamil Nadu

June 2013 to June 2017

Skills

- Python (Scikit-learn, Pandas, PyCharm, PySpark)
- R (dplyr, ggplot, Shiny)
- SQL
- MSSQL
- Oracle SQL
- PostgreSQL
- MySQL
- Machine Learning
- Big Data
- Salesforce
- CRM
- Tableau
- Power BI
- SAS
- Google Analytics
- Zoho CRM and Analytics
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft PowerPoint
- VISIO
- Advanced Excel
- JIRA
- Microsoft Project
- CRM
- ArcGIS
- ANOVA
- JMP
- Project Management
- Customer On-boarding
- Data Visualization
- Data Modeling
- KPI Dashboards
- Predictive Modeling
- Regression
- Written and Verbal Communication
- Problem Solving
- Conflict Resolution
- Teamwork

- Survival Analytics
- Data analytics
- Databases
- Relational databases

Links

http://linkedin.com/in/pharshitha

Certifications and Licenses

Salesforce Certification